[{"question":"Unlike the Tigris and Euphrates, the  ______  flooded at the same time every year, so farmers could predict when to plant their crops.","options":[{},"Nile river"],"extras":[],"answer":"Nile river"},{"question":" ______  cut the stems into strips, pressed them, and dried them into sheets that could be rolled into scrolls.","options":["Egyptians","Algerian","Bantu","Angolan"],"extras":["Basotho","Beninese","Berber","Black African"],"answer":"Egyptians"},{"question":"As in many ancient societies, much of the knowledge of  ______  came about as priests studied the world to find ways to please the gods.","options":["Egypt",{}],"extras":[],"answer":"Egypt"},{"question":"About 5,000 years ago, they noticed that a star now called Sirius appeared shortly before the  ______  began to flood.","options":["Nile",{}],"extras":[],"answer":"Nile"},{"question":"Unlike the Tigris and  ______ , the Nile River flooded at the same time every year, so farmers could predict when to plant their crops.","options":["Euphrates",{}],"extras":[],"answer":"Euphrates"},{"question":"Unlike the  ______  and Euphrates, the Nile River flooded at the same time every year, so farmers could predict when to plant their crops.","options":[{},"Tigris"],"extras":[],"answer":"Tigris"},{"question":"Historians divide ancient Egyptian dynasties into the  ______ , the Middle Kingdom, and the New Kingdom.","options":["Old kingdom",{}],"extras":[],"answer":"Old kingdom"},{"question":" ______ , Black Land The ancient Egyptians lived in narrow bands of land on each side of the Nile.","options":["Red land",{}],"extras":[],"answer":"Red land"},{"question":"It combined the red  ______  of Lower Egypt with the white  ______  of Upper Egypt.","options":[{},"Crown"],"extras":[],"answer":"Crown"},{"question":"The  ______  the Nile is 4,160 miles long—the world’s  ______ .","options":[{},"Longest river"],"extras":[],"answer":"Longest river"},{"question":"It combined the red Crown of  ______  with the white Crown of Upper Egypt.","options":["Lower egypt",{}],"extras":[],"answer":"Lower egypt"},{"question":"Legend says a king named  ______  and Lower Egypt.","options":["Narmer united upper",{}],"extras":[],"answer":"Narmer united upper"},{"question":"It begins near the equator in Africa and flows north to the  ______ .","options":[{},"Mediterranean sea"],"extras":[],"answer":"Mediterranean sea"},{"question":"Nubia was the Egyptian name for the area of the upper Nile that had the richest gold mines in  ______ .","options":["Africa",{}],"extras":[],"answer":"Africa"},{"question":"After about 100 years, the Egyptians drove out the  ______  and began the New Kingdom.","options":[{},"Hyksos"],"extras":[],"answer":"Hyksos"}]